# MICHAEL HUFFMAN

ENTERPRISE PROJECT LEADER









### **SKILLS**

MongoDB

**API** Configurations

Business Analysis

GitHub

Microsoft Office Suite 365

HTML, CSS, JS, JSON, SASS

Bootstrap

AWS, Heroku

jQuery

Angular

Responsive Design

SQL and Postgresql

Fluency in English

Project Management

Team Player

Organizational Leadership

Operation Innovation and Management

Change Management

Cross Functional Team Leadership

Creative Problem Solving

Strategic Planning

Performance Management

Business Intelligence

Development & Retention

### **EDUCATION**

# Full Stack Web Development: CareerFoundry

Certificate in Business Analysis:

Villanova University

**Associate in Business:** Lincoln College of Technology

Master Technician Degree in Master Technician Degree program: Lincoln College of Technology

# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

2+ years of website development and ensuring usability and improving user experience through project life cycles; writing clean code, testing across devices, debugging, and deployment. 19+ years of experience in Customer Success Management and Project Leadership.

# **EXPERIENCE**

#### Full Stack Developer

PortfolioDeux- (2020-present)

- https://github.com/mekanik20/PortfolioDeux
- Created a responsive single page portfolio site using JavaScript, CSS, HTML and inserted images and links for multiple projects listed
  - Debugged errors in code through problem solving using the terminal
  - Managed sprints of code through Kanban
  - Built the frontend and backend of a small movie website, including authenticating users and allowing users to create and change their personal profile information
  - Developed a small, serverless, progressive web application using TDD and fetches information from the Google Calendar API
  - Constructed a small web application that loads data from an external API and returns selection to user
  - Produced a mobile chat app for mobile devices through React Native
  - Consistently participating in coding exercises, updating code, and beginning new projects with the aim of progressing skillsets

# Service Advisor

Multiple Dealerships (Nissan, Volkswagen, Audi, Kia)- (2011-present)

- Drove continuous improvements to facilitate exceptional team output and customer service, efficiency, quality, and overall excellence in all phases of service
- Led the center's daily operations to achieve specific goals in productivity, quality, output, cost as well as revenue / margin where applicable
- Set the standard for open communication, active problem solving, and a positive work environment; built a team of top talent and mentored the next generation providing regular coaching and feedback
- Actively monitored customer service trends to make necessary improvements and assist your team in developing appropriate standards and processes to continuously elevate the overall service experience
- Coordinated and provided customer and employee communications on all policy, service, and contractual requirements
- Monitored integrity of contract data and identified/corrected areas of non-compliance
- Led, coached, trained, and motivated a team of Senior Account Executives to acquire new business targeting the enterprise market
- Diligently summarized customer concerns to ensure proper diagnosis and accurate estimates, selling recommended work, answering phone calls, collaborated with customers over multiple forms of contact

# Sales Representative | Project Manager

Kitchen Tune-Up (2020-2020)

- Executed customer-centric strategies leading to customer satisfaction
- Increased sold revenue from \$1,500 per rep per month to \$3,600
- Fostered a high-performance culture by motivating teams and developing customer relationships and engagement
- Adopted an eternal learner mindset absorbing key aspects of the industry related to arranging, organizing, managing people, and general administrative support
- Established relationships with key legislative and agency representatives